sabacloud.com 2014-06-19

# Saba Talent Management Systems | Unified Learning Platforms | LMS

PRIVACY POLICY (THE “POLICY”)

Last Revised February, 2014

This Policy applies to Saba Software, Inc., and its affiliated entities throughout the world (collectively referred to as “Saba,” “we,” or “us.”). Saba is committed to protecting your personal information. For that reason, Saba created this Policy which explains what personal information Saba collects about you, the purposes for which it uses and shares this information and how we safeguard that information. If you do not agree to the privacy practices described in the Policy, please do not use "www.saba.com" or related sites (collectively, the “Site”).

Saba has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. This privacy policy covers the Web sites www.saba.com and sabex.centra.com, collectively (“Web site”) The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software.   TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [privacy1@saba.com](mailto:privacy1@saba.com).  If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here.](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint)

_S_ aba complies with the U.S. – EU Safe Harbor framework and the U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from the European Union and from Switzerland, and Saba has certified its adherence to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement.  To learn more about the Safe Harbor Framework, and to view Saba’s certification, please visit [http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/.](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/)

**What this Policy Applies To**

The personal information covered by this Policy (“Personal Information”) includes, but is not limited to, personal information that is collected online at the Site and personal information that Saba receives from its clients pertaining to contractors, customers and related parties of the clients ((a) and (b) collectively referred to as "Users").

**Collection of Personal Information**

Saba collects Personal Information such as names, addresses, telephone numbers, email addresses and birth-dates. For example, if you submit a webinar registration to us online, we will collect your e-mail address. If you use Saba’s software through one of our clients, you may be asked to input information into an individual profile. This profile may include your name, registrations, certifications, qualifications, Centra sessions attended, employment information and/or other information. Users may also be asked to select a password. We also collect Users' names, companies, industries, postal addresses, email addresses and/or phone numbers when they register to receive certain information from us and/or our Site. Personal Information collected by Saba may be stored in the US or any other country in which Saba or its agents maintain facilities.

We receive permission to post written and video testimonials that include personal information prior to posting on our Web site.

If you use our blogs on this Web site, you should be aware that any personal information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages.  We are not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in these forums. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial and blog, you can contact us at [privacy1@saba.com](mailto:privacy1@saba.com).

On occasion, we have access to sensitive Personal Information of Users provided to us by clients located in the EU and/or in Switzerland. This sensitive Personal Information may include racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership, financial records, health information, sexual orientation and/or alleged commission of an offense. Saba will not disclose such sensitive Personal Information to a non-agent third party or use it for a purpose other than the purpose for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized, unless the individual explicitly consents or a legal exception applies.

**Use of Personal Information**

Saba uses Personal Information to:

  * Confirm and fill orders for products and services;
  * Assist clients with learning and people management requirements,  and collaboration sessions;
  * Perform professional services;
  * Administer accounts and provide support;
  * Maintain databases and subscription lists;
  * Process job applications;
  * Update databases;
  * Alert Users to product upgrades, special offers, updated information and other new or complimentary products and services;
  * Deliver services, such as newsletters, events, training and software requested by Users;
  * Create and publish content relevant to Users;
  * Provide Users with access to limited-entry areas of our Site as appropriate;
  * Otherwise conduct its business operations; and
  * Contact Users as necessary for the above purposes.

We will not use Personal Information for any other purpose incompatible with the purposes listed above, unless it is required or authorized by you, is in your own vital interest or is necessary to comply with a legal obligation. Your Personal Information may be shared with Saba business affiliates in a manner consistent with the Policy.  At any time, if you do not wish your Personal Information to be shared with any Saba business affiliates, please contact Saba Customer Service by [clicking here](mailto:supportinquiries@saba.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy%20request). With respect to Personal Information provided by clients, Saba uses such Personal Information solely for the purposes of performing tasks on behalf of, and under the instruction of, our clients as their service provider.

**Use of Personal Information by Third Parties**

Personal Information may be shared with third party agents who provide products and/or services to Saba and it customers, such as web site hosting, information technology consulting, web site management, foreign language support, complementary products and services requested by Users, data analysis, audit, legal, administrative, back-up, security, marketing and promotion.. Saba works to ensure that such third parties use the Personal Information only for the purposes for which we engage them (or our customers request of them)  and under similar privacy protection to what we maintain.

In the event there is a change in Saba's corporate structure, including, without limitation, merger, consolidation, sale, liquidation or transfer of substantial assets, Saba may, in its sole and absolute discretion, transfer, sell or assign information collected, including, without limitation, aggregated information and Personal Information, to one or more affiliated or unaffiliated third parties, as part of such restructuring.  Any affected Users will be notified via our Site or email.  Saba may also disclose Personal Information in order to: (1) comply with applicable laws; (2) respond to governmental inquiries or requests; (3) comply with valid legal processes; (4) protect the rights, privacy, safety or property of Saba, Site visitors, clients or the public; (5) enforce our Site terms of service; and (6) permit us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain.

**Direct Marketing**

By submitting information on the Site, Users may receive promotional email updates about products and services related to their requests.  If, at any time, you would like to discontinue receiving any such email updates, you may unsubscribe by following the unsubscribe instructions included in each promotional email.   

**Third Party Promotions**

We may also ask Site Users to choose whether to allow Saba to share their Personal Information with third parties for marketing purposes. We will honor the choices made. If you subsequently decide that you no longer wish to receive promotional emails from Saba, or if you no longer wish to allow Saba to share your Personal Information on a going-forward basis for marketing purposes with third parties, you may opt-out of receiving such emails or from such sharing as described below in the Access and Correction section.

We will endeavor to comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable. Please note that if you opt-out as described above, we will not be able to remove your Personal Information from the databases of third parties with which we have already shared your Personal Information (i.e., to which we have already provided your Personal Information as of the date that we implement your opt-out request). If you wish to cease receiving marketing-related emails from such third parties, please contact such third parties directly or utilize any opt-out mechanisms set forth in their respective privacy policies or marketing-related emails.

**Use of “Cookies” and Other Tracking Technologies**

When you use the Site, we, or third parties authorized by us, may collect certain technical and routing information about your computer to facilitate your use of the Site and its services. For example, we may log environmental variables, such as browser type, operating system, CPU speed, and the Internet Protocol address of your computer. We use these environmental variables to facilitate and track your use of the Site and its services. Saba may also use such environmental variables to measure traffic patterns on the Site and, in certain cases, to bring opportunities of potential interest to your intention. While it is possible that some data may be traceable to an individual, any such linked information will be treated in accordance with this Policy as long as it is so linked.

Saba uses "cookies" or similar technologies to store login and general information on visitors' computers. A cookie is a small amount of information that a web site transfers to a computer's hard drive. We use cookies to simplify visitors' access and to tailor our services to visitors' needs and interests. In some cases, we offer visitors the choice of having an ID or password stored in a cookie so that visitors do not need to re-enter it when they return to the Site. For these purposes personal information (such as email address) is tied to some of our cookies No other site can read a cookie set by Saba, and we cannot read a cookie that another web site wrote to a visitor's computer. Most Internet browsers are set to accept cookies. Users can reset browsers to refuse cookies and still use our Site, although access may be slower and less convenient.

We also may collect data by using "pixel tags," "web beacons," "clear GIFs" or similar means (collectively, " tags") that allow us to know when you visit our Site. Through tags, we do not have access to personal information about you, but we obtain aggregate data (i.e., the IP address and the domain name, the areas of the Site you visit, your operating system, your browser version and the URL you came from) which can be used to enhance your online experience.

Some of our business partners (i.e. tracking utility company) use cookies and web beacons on our site. We have no access or control of these third party tracking technologies.

**External Links**

The Site may include links to other web sites not controlled by Saba. Please note that we are not responsible for the collection, use, maintenance, sharing, or disclosure of data and/or information by such third parties. Once you leave our Site (you can usually tell where you are by checking the URL in the location bar on your browser), use of any information you provide is governed by the privacy policy of the operator of the site you are visiting. That policy may differ from ours. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of web sites that you visit before submitting personal information. If you can't find the privacy policy of any of these web sites via a link from the web site's homepage, you should contact the web site directly for more information.

**Social Media Widgets**

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button [and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site]. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

**Security and Confidentiality**

Saba takes appropriate and commercially reasonable technical and organizational measures to protect Personal Information against unauthorized access, accidental loss or damage and unauthorized destruction. Saba employees who handle confidential, proprietary or personal information are required to treat it confidentially and are not permitted to use it for purposes unrelated to Saba's business or disclose it to unauthorized third parties.

For online financial transactions, we use technology (including encryption) to protect the personal information that you transmit to us via our Site. Unfortunately, however, no security system or system of transmitting data over the Internet can be guaranteed to be entirely secure. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure, please notify us of the problem by contacting us at [privacy1@saba.com.](mailto:privacy1@saba.com)

**Data Retention**

We will not keep Personal Information longer than as necessary for the fulfillment of the purposes outlined herein. We seek to avoid the retention of unnecessary or duplicative information.

**Data Integrity**

Saba takes reasonable steps to ensure that the Personal Information it maintains is reliable for, and relevant to, its intended use. We also endeavor to ensure that such Information is accurate, complete and current.

**Access, Deletion and Correction**

Where required by applicable law, Saba provides Users with the right to access, delete and correct their Personal Information that Saba controls. For information about how to exercise these rights, or to unsubscribe from our newsletters, or if applicable, from our continuing to share information with third parties for their marketing purposes, please contact Saba Customer Service by [clicking here](mailto:supportinquiries@saba.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy%20request). We will respond to all requests for access within 30 days.

**Policy Updates**

We may update this Policy from time to time. When we do so, changes in our Policy will be effective immediately upon posting the revised Policy to the Site. If you are a regular visitor to this Site, we recommend that you check this Policy on a regular basis. By continuing to use the Site after a revised Policy has been posted, you will be deemed to have agreed to Policy changes. If you do not agree with the terms of this Policy, please do not continue using this Site.  If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page prior to the change becoming effective.

Changes to this Policy will be posted on the Site "/us/privacy-policy/". You should visit the Site periodically to review the most recent Policy.

**Contact Information**

Questions regarding this Policy should be directed to Saba at [legal@saba.com](mailto:legal@saba.com) or by contacting us at:

Saba Software, Inc.  
Attn: Legal Dept.  
2400 Bridge Parkway  
Redwood Shores, CA 94065  
USA
